<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Music on [Mathie@josh]#</title>
    <link>//localhost:37865/tags/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Music on [Mathie@josh]#</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 14:05:43 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//localhost:37865/tags/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Musical Impact</title>
      <link>//localhost:37865/posts/blog/first_blog_post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 14:05:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:37865/posts/blog/first_blog_post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;impactful&#34;&gt;Impactful&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Music. There are hundreds, thousands even, of genres of music in the world, and
new and emerging types are being created every day. The impact music has on
this world is astronomical and is completely different for every single person.Someone once asked me: If music is so impactful, which ones are impactful to me, and why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-musical-history&#34;&gt;My Musical History&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe, remembering back the one Genre of music that impacted me so much in
my young life was The Great Scottish Highland Bagpipe music. My grandfather was born and raised in Scotland, married a beautiful English woman, had three amazing children and moved to America when my mother was a child. Growing up in a English/Scottish household introduced me to the mystical drones of the bagpipe at a very early age. To this day the sounds of Bagpipes bring a wave of emotions to me. Happiness, excitement, sadness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;impactful&#34;&gt;Impactful&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Music. There are hundreds, thousands even, of genres of music in the world, and
new and emerging types are being created every day. The impact music has on
this world is astronomical and is completely different for every single person.Someone once asked me: If music is so impactful, which ones are impactful to me, and why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-musical-history&#34;&gt;My Musical History&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe, remembering back the one Genre of music that impacted me so much in
my young life was The Great Scottish Highland Bagpipe music. My grandfather was born and raised in Scotland, married a beautiful English woman, had three amazing children and moved to America when my mother was a child. Growing up in a English/Scottish household introduced me to the mystical drones of the bagpipe at a very early age. To this day the sounds of Bagpipes bring a wave of emotions to me. Happiness, excitement, sadness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grew up listening to music that my grandparents enjoyed: Such as Shirley
Bassey, Classical music, Bobby Vinton, and the like. My mother introduced me to
one of the most impactful genres of music that open a flood gate to music that
today still impacts me the most. She introduced me to Hard Rock with Billy
Idols &amp;ldquo;White Wedding&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through Billy Idol I found other Rock and Metal bands. Twisted Sister, David
Bowie, Duran Duran, The Cars, Tears for Fears and a plethora of other bands
from the late 80&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;defining-me&#34;&gt;Defining ME&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the most impactful bands from this era that,
shaped who I am today were : The Cure, Joy Division, The Sisters of
Mercy, Bauhaus, Siouxsie and the Banshees, London After Midnight, and Skinny
Puppy. Classified under the gloriously named genre of &amp;ldquo;Goth Music&amp;rdquo; the dark and
macabre themes paved my early teens years (Cliche I now). Through that love of dark music I found a love for Punk and Heavy Metal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I grew up in the 90&amp;rsquo; I fell in love with genres like: Grunge, Ska,
Ska-punk,and Techno (and its hundreds of sub Genres). This eclectic musical
interest has followed me throughout my teens and adulthood, and I am still to
this day finding new and amazing music that will continue to impact me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
