<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>[Mathie@josh]#</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on [Mathie@josh]#</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 14:05:43 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Musical Impact</title>
      <link>/posts/blog/first_blog_post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 14:05:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/blog/first_blog_post/</guid>
      <description>Impactful  Music. There are hundreds, thousands even, of genres of music in the world, and new and emerging types are being created every day. The impact music has on this world is astronomical and is completely different for every single person.Someone once asked me: If music is so impactful, which ones are impactful to me, and why?
My Musical History I believe, remembering back the one Genre of music that impacted me so much in my young life was The Great Scottish Highland Bagpipe music.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up Vim</title>
      <link>/posts/tutorials/set_up_vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 12:16:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tutorials/set_up_vim/</guid>
      <description>Vim needs no introduction.  Well that&amp;rsquo;s not entirely true, it probably does if you have never heard of it. vim or Vi IMproved, is a well known port of the vi editor created by Bill Joy, that was created by Bram Moolenaar. vim was designed as a more improved text editor over the original vi, with a heavy influence on the use of the keyboard over the mouse, and pre-installed movement commands, or custom macros, to traverse the document you are creating or editing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Termux</title>
      <link>/posts/tutorials/install_termux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 18:20:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tutorials/install_termux/</guid>
      <description>Today I would like to go through how I Installed Termux on my Android phone, how I edited the app, what applications I use it for, why I installed it, and what I have learned.
First What is Termux you might ask? Pulled directly form the main website https://www.termux.com:
 Termux is an Android terminal emulator and Linux environment app that works directly with no rooting or setup required. A minimal base system is installed automatically - additional packages are available using the APT package manager.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi there  I am Josh Mathie. Welcome to my website! A little about me:
 I&amp;rsquo;m currently pursing (Albeit on a break) a Bachelors Degree in Electronics Engineering Technology, with a major focus in Electronics Design and Integrations at Daytona State College. I am also interested in IT and networking.  Looking to get my Linux+, CCNA, Network+, and CompTIA A+ sometime in the future.   I prefer FOSS (Free Open Source Software), such as: GIMP, Krita, Audacity and KiCad  What is my website all about?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
