<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>[Mathie@josh]#</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/posts/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on [Mathie@josh]#</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 12:56:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//localhost:1313/posts/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Life updates!</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/blog/life-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 12:56:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/blog/life-updates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;life-updates&#34;&gt;Life Updates&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick update as its been almost a year since i was in the hospital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heart failure has become manageable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have changed my diet. I eat a mostly whole- food plant based diet.
I do still eat meat once in a while (maybe 2-3 times a month) but on
average its a WFPB diet. This is also as a Low sodium (less than 1500mg
a day, no more than 2900mg a day, unless its a special instance that
I will change me day before and day after to accomodate the increase.)
as low sugar as possible , and very minimal amounts of oils.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;life-updates&#34;&gt;Life Updates&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick update as its been almost a year since i was in the hospital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heart failure has become manageable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have changed my diet. I eat a mostly whole- food plant based diet.
I do still eat meat once in a while (maybe 2-3 times a month) but on
average its a WFPB diet. This is also as a Low sodium (less than 1500mg
a day, no more than 2900mg a day, unless its a special instance that
I will change me day before and day after to accomodate the increase.)
as low sugar as possible , and very minimal amounts of oils.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have greatly increased my exercise, trying for 10K steps a day, as
well as 30-45 min of moderately intense exercise 3-5 days a week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have lost nearly 50 lbs since my hospital visit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have gotten my BP under control and have increased my EF (Ejection
Fraction) from sub 20% to 45%. Still not to the recommended 55-65%, but feel
significantly better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have learned to enjoy my life much more. Knowing that i have a diesese
that can be possibly reversed, or at least managed for the long term, i have
acknowledged that life is short, and can change at any moment, and that it
needs to be enjoyed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall my cardiologist believes I can make a great recovery and get my heart
back up to the healthy level it needs to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life Changes . . . For the Better</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/blog/life-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 08:27:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/blog/life-changes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;life-changes---&#34;&gt;Life Changes . . .&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have never been one to really take care of myself. I tend to care for others
before I even consider my own self. I have always been quite overweight, for most
of my life. I never took Gym seriously in Middle School and High School, and
never really openly worked out or exercised, beside the occasional bicycle
ride and walks. I never openly eat the healthiest of foods. Processed meals and
fast food are the stables of the american diet, and for someone who previously
worked a dead end job for nearly ten years, and had to either &lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;. Pay my own
bills with the very limited amount of money I had to myself, &lt;strong&gt;B&lt;/strong&gt;. Split bills with
roommates, Most processed food and fast food were the cheapest things I could
afford. Now that i&amp;rsquo;m older, I completely regret it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;life-changes---&#34;&gt;Life Changes . . .&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have never been one to really take care of myself. I tend to care for others
before I even consider my own self. I have always been quite overweight, for most
of my life. I never took Gym seriously in Middle School and High School, and
never really openly worked out or exercised, beside the occasional bicycle
ride and walks. I never openly eat the healthiest of foods. Processed meals and
fast food are the stables of the american diet, and for someone who previously
worked a dead end job for nearly ten years, and had to either &lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;. Pay my own
bills with the very limited amount of money I had to myself, &lt;strong&gt;B&lt;/strong&gt;. Split bills with
roommates, Most processed food and fast food were the cheapest things I could
afford. Now that i&amp;rsquo;m older, I completely regret it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-happened&#34;&gt;What happened..&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I had my first daughter, my wife and I decided to move away from my hometown
so I could continue my schooling (more on that later). I found an amazing job
that has taught me so much, and has some of the best people I have ever met,
Much better than the crappy job I held for over a decade that just added to my
growing stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I digress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We moved here and I felt that something wasn&amp;rsquo;t right, and felt like i was
having some issues. Cue the doctors visit to find out I had high blood
pressure. Not unbelievable since exercise and diet were not my focus points for
most of my life, and High blood pressure and heart problems run in my family.
The doctor put me on high blood pressure medicine that helped tremendously.
I started to change my diet slightly, and felt better. Then me and my wife were
surprised with our second daughter. I fell of the wagon, but continued to take
my medicine. For a time.. then stupidly stopped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward two years, and i decide i&amp;rsquo;ve had enough and get on a diet.
I keep the diet going for several months. Lose nearly 50 Lbs, and feel better
than ever. Then stress hits me like a brick and I fall back into my horrible
eating habits.. gain all that I weight lost back, and make myself worse and more
miserable. Cut to a few weeks ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I felt like I was getting sick, like very sick, and with everything going
on in the world with Covid, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to chance my kids getting it. I go
to the hospital, they scold me or not taking my blood pressure medicines,
(which I did start taking again, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t get refills on because my
previous PCP dropped his younger patients, and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to find another in
time.) Do the test for Covid, and an X-Ray and find out that I do show signs of
Bronchial Pneumonia very prominent in patients with Covid. So the give me
some medications and send me on my way. Later that day I get a negative result
on my Covid, thank the gods. I started taking the medicines right
away, and started feeling significantly better. Then a week later I started feeling
worse, still unable to breath, getting heavily winded after walking up the
stairs etc. One evening I went to sleep, and couldn&amp;rsquo;t fall asleep and just
thought it was insomnia or something. Then an anxiety like panic came over me,
and I just didn&amp;rsquo;t feel right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have an at home BP machine because of my hypertension, so I checked my BP. It
was highly elevated, almost borderline Hypertension stage 3. Anxiety
skyrocketed at that point. So I rechecked it 15 minutes later. Still very very
high. &amp;lsquo;Ok It&amp;rsquo;s probably from my anxiety&amp;rsquo; I thought to myself. So I checked it
again 15 minutes later. Higher than before. I rush to the ER and have to wait
as the hospital is completely full, of Covid patients. I almost leave because
i&amp;rsquo;m still very panicky, and feel like my BP hasn&amp;rsquo;t dropped any, and think the other hospital across town may be faster. But something in me just tells me to not leave. After waiting nearly 12 hours, I feel better finally, and I&amp;rsquo;m finally taken back, they give me medicine for my BP and put me in an isolation room, because they too feel that this is covid, even though my previous test was negative. While in the waiting room I started getting short of breath again, and they came to get me for an X-ray. Unbeknownst to me they were doing something called a &amp;ldquo;walk test&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This test is typically done for around 3 minutes, which is about the time it
took to walk from the waiting room to the X-ray room. By the time I got to the
X-ray I was completely out of breath and having a difficult time holding my
breath for the xrays. After walking back and waiting for a few moments i&amp;rsquo;m escorted to a ED
room where the nurse tells me they believe based on the X-ray failing the walk,
They believe it is not Pneumonia, but CHF, Congestive heart failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;say-what-but-your-young&#34;&gt;Say what? But your young?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They admitted me to the ER, gave me medicine to calm down because not going to
lie I kind of lost my shit and cried. Being told that you might have heart
failure at 33, with two beautiful toddlers and a loving wife at home, is like
a major kick to your entire existence and tends to make anyone become a puddle.
They were able to admit me to a room, started a few different medicine
regimens to see how I reacted and to monitor me. They did an echocardiogram and
confirmed that I do indeed have early onset Congestive Heart Failure and high
cholesterol levels. I spent
a good bit of my time in the hospital losing my shit at least four times a day,
mostly berating myself for letting myself get like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I would have just ate better, if I would have just exercised more, if
I would have just kept my BP under control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily the doctor told me that with me being young, I have a great chance to
make my heart better, not 100%, it will never be 100%, but better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;whats-changed&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s changed?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve completely overhauled my diet. Cut my sodium intake to the recommended
1500 mg a day. Started eating lots more vegetables, fruits, and whole
grains. Cut red meat out nearly entirely (got to have a steak every once in
a while), started eating more chicken, turkey and fish. I track everything
I eat with Cronometer and try to meet or be below the recommended calorie intake it
recommends. I&amp;rsquo;ve lost nearly 10 Lbs already so that&amp;rsquo;s a plus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought an exercise bike so I can exercise more. Have realized how out of
shape I am once I got on it for the first time. I used to be able to ride
a bike for miles without any issue. I was on the bike for 20 minutes and
felt like I was dying. I also have been trying to meet 10K steps a day,
which I sadly haven&amp;rsquo;t been solid on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Been trying to get enough sleep. This was always a problem for me, so
getting 8 hours a day has been a nice adjustment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trying to not stress myself out as much as I have in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-now&#34;&gt;What now?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now? I keep living my life! I have two amazing kids that need their dad. I have
an amazing wife, that needs her best friend. I have so much more to do in my
life, and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;M GOING TO STICK TO THESE CHANGES. BECAUSE I HAVE TO MANY PEOPLE
THAT DEPEND ON ME.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LIFE YOUR LIFE! But please, be mindful and eat healthy, and TAKE CARE OF YOUR
SELF!!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musical Impact</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/blog/first_blog_post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 14:05:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/blog/first_blog_post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;impactful&#34;&gt;Impactful&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Music. There are hundreds, thousands even, of genres of music in the world, and
new and emerging types are being created every day. The impact music has on
this world is astronomical and is completely different for every single person.Someone once asked me: If music is so impactful, which ones are impactful to me, and why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-musical-history&#34;&gt;My Musical History&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe, remembering back the one Genre of music that impacted me so much in
my young life was The Great Scottish Highland Bagpipe music. My grandfather was born and raised in Scotland, married a beautiful English woman, had three amazing children and moved to America when my mother was a child. Growing up in a English/Scottish household introduced me to the mystical drones of the bagpipe at a very early age. To this day the sounds of Bagpipes bring a wave of emotions to me. Happiness, excitement, sadness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;impactful&#34;&gt;Impactful&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Music. There are hundreds, thousands even, of genres of music in the world, and
new and emerging types are being created every day. The impact music has on
this world is astronomical and is completely different for every single person.Someone once asked me: If music is so impactful, which ones are impactful to me, and why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-musical-history&#34;&gt;My Musical History&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe, remembering back the one Genre of music that impacted me so much in
my young life was The Great Scottish Highland Bagpipe music. My grandfather was born and raised in Scotland, married a beautiful English woman, had three amazing children and moved to America when my mother was a child. Growing up in a English/Scottish household introduced me to the mystical drones of the bagpipe at a very early age. To this day the sounds of Bagpipes bring a wave of emotions to me. Happiness, excitement, sadness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grew up listening to music that my grandparents enjoyed: Such as Shirley
Bassey, Classical music, Bobby Vinton, and the like. My mother introduced me to
one of the most impactful genres of music that open a flood gate to music that
today still impacts me the most. She introduced me to Hard Rock with Billy
Idols &amp;ldquo;White Wedding&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through Billy Idol I found other Rock and Metal bands. Twisted Sister, David
Bowie, Duran Duran, The Cars, Tears for Fears and a plethora of other bands
from the late 80&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;defining-me&#34;&gt;Defining ME&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the most impactful bands from this era that,
shaped who I am today were : The Cure, Joy Division, The Sisters of
Mercy, Bauhaus, Siouxsie and the Banshees, London After Midnight, and Skinny
Puppy. Classified under the gloriously named genre of &amp;ldquo;Goth Music&amp;rdquo; the dark and
macabre themes paved my early teens years (Cliche I now). Through that love of dark music I found a love for Punk and Heavy Metal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I grew up in the 90&amp;rsquo; I fell in love with genres like: Grunge, Ska,
Ska-punk,and Techno (and its hundreds of sub Genres). This eclectic musical
interest has followed me throughout my teens and adulthood, and I am still to
this day finding new and amazing music that will continue to impact me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
